JOSEPH FITZSIMMONS

WEB DEVELOPER



DENVER, CO



314.304.8268



joe@hoseb.com

SKILLS

- HTML / HTML5
- CSS / CSS3 / SASS / Compass
- JavaScript / jQuery
- Require JS
- JSHint
- Foundation
- AJAX / FLEX
- XML / XSL
- JSON / SOAP
- Jira
- Git / Subversion
- Relational Database Concepts: PL/SQL, MySQL, MS SQL
- eCommerce: Demandware
- Adobe Suite: Photoshop, Flash, Dreamweaver
- CMS and Enterprise Apps: WordPress, Drupal, SharePoint
- Various IDEs: Eclipse, Visual Studio
- PHP
- SEO
- Analytics: Adobe Analytics, Google, Tealium Tag Management

EDUCATION & AWARDS

Vatterott College

St. Louis, MO. 2004-2006 Associates of Science: Information Systems

Demandware

DW Developer Certified in 2013

IABC

Bronze Quill Award 2010

Step Two Designs

Intranet Innovation Award 2008

PROFILE

Web developer with nine years' experience creating and managing sites for major companies in both the financial and retail sectors. Excels in meeting simultaneous long and short-term deadlines and ushering projects from inception to delivery. Shared roles in multiple top-down redesigns for global sites, one of which exceeded an optimistic quarterly sales goal of 15 million dollars for NewBalance.com.

EXPERIENCE

ST. LOUIS, MO.

NEW BALANCE eCommerce Web Developer 06/2013 - 05/2015

FOCUSED SKILLS:

HTML | CSS | JS | AJAX | XML JSON | Jira | Git | eCommerce

- Developed international sites using HTML, CSS, and JS, including various libraries, extensions and preprocessors.
- Documented technical solutions in response to enhancement and optimization requests regarding New Balance's eCommerce websites by utilizing several Atlassian tools.
- Participated and led coding of solutions and assisted with quality assurance activities including unit testing, system testing and solution validation.
- Ensured that best practices followed web standards and sites were fluid on all browsers, devices and screens.
- Worked with numerous RESTful Web Services and APIs from eCommerce vendors.

ST. LOUIS, MO.

SCOTTRADE

Intranet Developer 03/2009 - 05/2013

HTML | CSS | JS | AJAX | XML SOAP | PL/SQL | Adobe Suite

- Was responsible for the implementation and coding of all CSS, jQuery, JavaScript and HTML for the Scottrade Intranet.
- Was point of contact for all projects and applications and reviewed all Work Requests from varying departments within Scottrade.
- Worked with third party vendors to consume API's, track site analytics, improve SEO and site usability.
- Marketed, promoted and branded website using style guides, banners, general promotions and streamlined processes with reusable pages, templates and styles.

ST. LOUIS, MO.

SCOTTRADE

Intranet Administrator and Content Engineer 12/2006 - 03/2009

HTML | CSS | JS | AJAX | XML Sharepoint | CMS | PHP | SEO

- Was involved in applications from development to production and facilitated QA, UAT and Regression Testing for enhancements.
- Gathered functional requirements, created technical specifications and maintained competitive architecture with other businesses.
- · Administrated permissions and roles for secured content.
- Answered support calls and delegated responsibilities to co-workers.

ST. LOUIS, MO.

SCOTTRADE

Corporate Communications Intern 03/2006 - 12/2006

HTML | CSS | JS | AJAX | XML Analytics | Adobe Suite | SEO

- · Assisted in conceptualization and execution of high-level technical plans.
- · Consulted with business groups to clarify requirements and feasibility.
- Helped to provide technical solutions and participated in discussions to expand knowledge of systems and processes.